-= 小红帽 =-
满月了  今晚锁好门窗
Full moon. Lock up tonight.
狼人带走猪  总比带走你好点
Better the wolf takes the pig than you.
我们住在黑暗森林的边缘
We lived on the edge of a dark forest.
我们的村子鲜有人知
Few knew our village by names
但不少人听说过这里骇人听闻的事件
but many had heard of the terrible things that happened there.
妈妈总对我说
My mother always told me,
别和陌生人说话
"Don't talk to strangers.
打完水马上回家
Go get water and come straight home."
我试着做个听话的乖乖女
I tried to be a good girI and do what she said.
瓦莱丽
Valerie.
相信我  我试过了
Believe me, I tried.
我们走
Let's go.
你带刀了吗
Do you have the knife?
带了
Right here.
看啊  雪白的毛
Look, snow white fur.
我可以给你做双猎靴
I'll make you a pair of hunting boots.
动手啊  彼得
Do it, Peter.
你动手
You do it.
不  你来动手
No, you do it.
十年后
收工吧
That's it.
我知道好女孩不该猎杀兔子
I know good girls aren't supposed to hunt rabbits
或独自走入树林
or go into the woods alone.
但打小起
But since we were kids,
他总有办法让我违反规则
he always had a way of making me wanna break the rules.
彼得  先吃饭再砍  树跑不了
Peter! Trees'll still be there after we eat.
还给我
Give me that.
你拿什么来换
What will you give me for it?
他们没告诉你吗
They didn't tell you?
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
他们决定把你嫁给亨利·拉扎
They've arranged for you to marry Henry Lazar.
我妈妈终于如愿了
Well, my mother finally got what she wanted.
得到金钱
Money.
亨利也如愿以偿了  得到了你
Henry gets what he's always wanted. You.
那我们怎么办
So, what do we do now?
你想嫁给他吗
Do you want to marry him?
你知道我不想
You know I don't.
证明
Prove it.
怎么证明
How?
和我一起私奔
Run away with me.
我们去哪里
Where would we go?
你想去哪里都行
Anywhere you want.
游弋于大海
The ocean.
混迹于都市
The city.
隐居于群山
The mountains.
你怕吗
You afraid?
-不怕   -不怕吗
- No. - Oh, no?
真的吗
Really?
你得离开家
You'd leave your home?
你的家人
Your family?
你的全部生活
Your whole life?
只要能和你在一起  我愿意做任何事
I would do anything to be with you.
我就知道你会这么说
I thought you'd say that.
美得你
Oh, did you?
心动不如马上行动
Let's do something about it.
等他们发现
We have half a day's ride
我们已经跑出半天的路程了
before anyone knows we're gone.
我会追上你
I'll race you.
狼人来了
The wolf.
在这里  这边
This way! Over here!
它又杀人了
It killed again.
可我们遵守约定  献祭过了啊
But we've kept the peace.
是狼人违背了约定
Well, the wolf has broken it.
被杀的是谁
Who is it?
告诉我
Tell me.
是你姐姐
It's your sister.
妈妈  爸爸
Mother, Father.
露西
Lucie!
谢谢你  克劳德
Thank you, Claude.
拉扎夫人  请进
Madame Lazar, please come in.
苏塞特
Suzette.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
谢谢
Thank you.
我来拿吧
Let me take that.
你好  亨利
Hello, Henry.
女士们好
Ladies.
露西是个好姑娘
Lucie was a good girl.
他现在是你的未婚夫了
He's your fiance now.
他过来致哀
He's come to offer his condolences.
但我一点不了解他
But I barely know him.
你得去了解他
You'll get to know him.
现在下去吧  求你了
Now go down there. Please.
塞泽尔
Cesaire.
跟我们去酒馆吧
Come with us to the tavern.
让女士们用她们自己的方式悼念
Let the women grieve in their own way.
我  我也要去
I-- I-- I want to go.
别去
No.
我嫁给你父亲的时候  并不爱他
I didn't love your father when we were first married.
那时的我深爱着另一个男人
I was in love with another man.
但我慢慢爱上了他
But I came to love your father.
还有了两个漂亮的女儿
And he gave me two beautiful daughters.
我们的祷告也管用吧
We should count our blessings.
得了吧  神父
Come on, Father.
狼人已经将近二十年没杀人了
It's been almost 20 years since the wolf has taken a human life.
二十年了
Twenty years.
那是因为每个满月
That's because we sacrifice
我们献上了最好的牲畜
our best livestock every full moon.
我们一直信守约定
We kept our end of the bargain.
现在我们要杀了它
So now we kill it.
对
Yeah!
我们杀了这畜生
Let's kill that thing!
不
No.
我请来了所罗门神父
I've summoned Father Solomon.
所罗门神父
Father Solomon?
他在全国各地
He has destroyed werewolves and witches
杀了不少狼人和巫女
in cities throughout the kingdom.
他会帮我们干掉这野兽
He will rid us of this beast.
不
No.
他会因为我们复仇心切而为所欲为
He'll rob us of our vengeance.
我奇怪她怎么会在月圆之夜出门呢
I wonder why she was outside on a wolf night.
也许是偷溜出去和男孩子约会吧
Maybe she snuck out to meet a boy.
露西绝不会满脑子想男人
My Lucie never even thought about boys.
她肯定迷上了我的孙子
She was certainly taken with my grandson.
她老是像只小狗一样缠着他
She used to come by and follow him about like a puppy.
出事那晚  她发现
She found out that night that
亨利和她妹妹订婚了
Henry was engaged to her sister.
她肯定悲痛欲绝
She must have been heartbroken.
也许她宁愿死  也不愿忍受没有他的日子
Maybe she chose to die rather than live without him.
太浪漫了
How romantic.
普鲁登斯
Prudence!
别乱说
It's unspeakable.
她从没告诉过我
She never even told me.
别想多了  亲爱的
Don't worry, dear.
亨利的视线从没离开过你
Henry always had his eye on you.
你是最漂亮的
You're the pretty one.
我是来致哀的
I'm paying my respects.
我知道你来干嘛
I know exactly why you're here.
我已经失去一个女儿
I've already lost one daughter.
瓦莱丽是我的所有
Valerie's all I have left.
你什么也给不了她
You have nothing to offer her.
我有工作  和你丈夫一样
I have a trade. The same one as your husband.
我知道樵夫能挣多少钱
I know what a woodcutter earns.
亨利是她幸福生活的唯一希望
Henry's her only hope for a better life.
如果你爱她...
If you love her...
就该放手
you'll let her go.
在通往格瑞摩尔山的小路上
We've all seen the bones
我们都见过散落的骸骨
on the trail to Mount Grimmoor.
狼人的老巢就在那里
That's where the wolf makes its lair.
我们知道狼人的弱点
We know the weaknesses of the werewolf.
它白天不能出没
It can't come out in daylight.
它不能踏上圣地
It can't step onto holy ground.
还怕银器
And there's silver.
银器可以杀死它
That'll kill it.
银器
Silver!
也许奥古斯特神父是对的
Maybe Father Auguste is right.
也许我们该等等
Maybe we should wait.
懦夫
Coward.
也许  我的孩子
Maybe, my son...
你该鼓起勇气
you should find your courage.
你们都想去猎狼吗
You want to hunt the wolf?
那我们就去抓它
Let's hunt it.
杀了它
Let's kill it!
杀了这野兽
Let's kill the beast!
杀了它
Let's kill it!
出什么事了
What's going on?
走吧  伙计们
Come on, boys!
跟我一起去猎狼
Are you with me?!
我们走
Let's go!
小心点
Be careful.
我失去了姐姐  不能再失去你
I lost my sister. I can't lose you too.
我们不能再这样了
We can't do this anymore.
你得听他们的  你得嫁给亨利
You have to go through with it. You have to marry Henry.
但你知道我想要的不是亨利
But you know I don't want Henry.
别想那些有的没的了
Don't make this something it's not.
我们曾有过欢乐  仅此而已
Look, we had our fun. That's all it ever was.
你说的不是真的
I don't believe you.
我做了东西给你
I made something for you.
本想在婚礼上给你  但...
I was gonna wait until our wedding, but, uh....
只是以防万一
Just in case.
你会快乐起来的
You will be happy again.
我保证
I promise.
走吧  亨利
Come on, Henry.
我们该等等
We should wait.
我们该等等所罗门神父
We should wait for Father Solomon.
不
No!
他明天就到了
He'll be here tomorrow!
我们会杀了狼人
We're gonna kill the wolf.
我们会结果它的
We can take care of this.
人齐了吗  还有人去吗
That's it? Nobody else?
我们出发
Let's go!
回家找你妈妈去
Go home to your mama's, then.
艾德里安  谢谢你为露西出头
Adrian. Thank you for standing up for Lucie.
那很不容易
That was no small thing.
我们就快成一家人了  换你也会这样做
We'll be family soon. You'd have done the same.
答应我  千万要小心
Promise me you'll be careful.
别担心
Don't worry.
狼人不要我  我全是骨头
The wolf doesn't want me. I'm all gristle.
我是认真的  儿子
I mean it, son.
我会小心的  妈妈
I promise, Mama.
奶奶
Grandmother.
亲爱的  亲爱的
Darling. Darling.
来吧
Come.
小心
Careful.
她还有很多事没告诉我
There are so many things she didn't tell me.
我是她妹妹  应该无话不谈
And I'm her sister. I should've known.
那是她的选择
That was her choice.
我们都有秘密
We all have secrets.
记得我奶奶以前常说
Remember what my grandma used to say:
-面包可以缓解忧伤  -缓解忧伤
- "All sorrows are less with bread."  - "Less with bread".
来  试一试
Here. Try this.
真漂亮
How beautiful.
这是我为了你的婚礼做的
I was making it for your wedding.
我不觉得这是我的婚礼
I don't feel like it's my wedding.
我觉得就像...
I feel like...
像是被卖了
I'm being sold.
就在那里
Right up there.
你最好小心点
You better watch yourself.
有岔口了
There's a fork.
我们分头行动
Let's split up.
又一个岔口
Another fork.
我们进陡峭的那个
We'll take the steep one.
不  我们该一起行动
No. We should stay together.
早上好  亲爱的
Good morning, dear.
早上好  奶奶
Morning, Grandmother.
奶奶告诉过我们
Grandmother told us that
狼人常常会灭了一家门
the wolf used to kill entire families...
从床上掳走孩子们
snatching children from their beds.
我从来不相信这些故事  直到现在
Those stories never seemed real to me. Until now.
撕碎这畜生
Ripped the thing out!
克劳德
Claude.
敬艾德里安
To Adrian.
为了他的献身
For his sacrifice.
敬艾德里安
To Adrian.
可怜的亨利
Poor Henry.
亨利
Henry.
你父亲是位勇士
Your father was a brave man.
知道吗  我离得很近  甚至能闻到它
You know, I was close enough to smell it.
但我害怕了  躲了起来
And I was afraid. And I hid from it.
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
我应该去救他
I should've saved him.
-亨利  -你走吧
- Henry... - Just leave!
我不想让你看到我这样
I don't want you to see me like this.
是亨利的父亲  对吗  你爱的人
It was Henry's father, wasn't it? The man you loved?
露西爱上了他
Lucie was in love with him.
她比我大一岁  她应该可以嫁给他的
She was a year older than me. She could've married him.
为什么非要我嫁呢
Why did you insist it was me?
我想你知道答案
I think you know the answer to that.
我要你亲口说出来
I want you to say it.
露西是亨利的同父异母的妹妹
Lucie was Henry's half-sister.
艾德里安是她的父亲
Adrian was her father.
爸爸知道吗
Does papa know about Lucie?
还不知道  你得保证严守这个秘密
No. And you have to promise me that you'll never tell.
所罗门神父
Father Solomon.
他来了
He's here.
克劳德
Claude.
阁下驾到
Presenting His Eminence....
所罗门神父
Father Solomon.
爸爸
Papa.
不要哭
Oh, please don't cry.
你们看  看到这些孩子了吗
You see? You see all these children?
他们多么害怕啊
You see how scared they are?
因为这里有一只大恶狼  得有人杀了它
There's a big, bad wolf. Someone has to stop it.
就是那只杀了我们妈妈的野兽吗
Is that the beast that killed our mother?
很有可能
It may very well be.
走吧  我随后就到
Go on. I'll join you soon.
不
No.
走吧
Go.
万分荣幸  阁下
This is indeed an honor, Your Eminence.
欢迎  你正好赶上了我们的狂欢
Welcome. You've arrived just in time for our festival.
正如你所见  狼人已经搞定了
As you can see, the werewolf has been dealt with.
这不是狼人
That is not a werewolf.
恕我冒昧
No disrespect...
我们整整两代人深受这畜生所害
but we have been living with this beast for two generations.
我们当然知道对付的是什么
We know what we're dealing with.
恕我冒昧
Well, no disrespect...
我看你们完全不知道要对付的是什么
but you have no idea what you are dealing with.
我也曾像你一样
I was like you once.
我妻子名叫佩内洛普
My wife's name was Penelope.
她给我生了两个漂亮的女儿
She gave me two beautiful daughters.
我们一家本来十分幸福
We were a very happy family.
我们住的村子也是这样
We lived in a village like this.
像剑角村一样
And like Daggerhorn...
我们村也曾受狼人侵扰
ours was plagued by a werewolf.
一个月圆之夜  我和朋友们喝醉了
One full moon, my friends and I got drunk.
我们决定追捕它
We decided to hunt it.
我们从没想过会找到它
It never occurred to us that we might actually find it,
但我们竟然真的找到了
but find it we did.
那畜生
It ripped...
把我最好的朋友撕成了两半
my best friend in half.
就那么一下
Quickly.
然后它扑向我
And then it was on me.
我举起斧头砍啊砍
I hacked and hacked at it with my axe.
突然
Suddenly...
它不见了
it was gone.
我砍下了它的一只前爪
I had cut off one of its front paws.
我想这是个不错的纪念品
I thought it might make a clever souvenir,
于是就拿回了家
and so l took it home.
结果发现
And there I found my wife...
我妻子手腕上缠着一块血淋淋的布
...with a bloody rag wrapped around her wrist.
我再打开袋子一看
And when I opened my sack...
狼人的爪子
the werewolf's paw...
不见了
was gone.
取而代之的是这个
This was in its place.
我告诉女儿是狼人杀了她们的妈妈
I told my girls the werewolf killed their mother.
但我骗了她们
But that was a lie.
是我杀了她
I killed her.
狼人死后会变回人形
When a werewolf dies, it returns to its human form.
而这只是一只普通的灰狼
That is just a common gray wolf.
你们的狼人
Your werewolf...
还活得好好的
is still very much alive.
这是教廷庇护的三把银剑之一
This is one of only three silver swords blessed by the Holy See.
我能摸一下吗
May I touch?
不行
No.
现在是危险时刻
This is a very dangerous time.
你们知道血月意味着什么
You all know what the Blood Moon means.
他们完全不知道
They have no idea what it means.
这是太阳系仪
The orrery.
这颗红色行星每隔13年跟月球连成一线
The red planet converges with the moon once every 13 years.
这是产生新狼人的唯一时间
This is the only time a new werewolf can be created.
在血月这一周
During the week of the Blood Moon...
只要被狼人咬一口就会受到诅咒
the werewolf may pass his curse on with a single bite.
在一般的月圆之夜  狼人只能咬死你
During a normal full moon, a wolf bite will kill you.
但是在血月时期
But during a Blood Moon...
你们的灵魂都无法幸免于难
your very souls are in danger.
这三天  血月亏减之前
Until the Blood Moon wanes in three days...
你们都不安全
you will never truly be safe.
我们现在安全了
We're safe now.
我杀了狼人  捣了它的老巢
I killed the wolf in its lair.
就在格瑞摩尔山上的洞里
The cave at Mount Grimmoor.
你们一开始就被这只畜生骗了
You have been deceived by this beast from the start.
让你们以为它住在格瑞摩尔
It made you think it lived on Grimmoor...
这样你们就不会在最容易发现的地方找寻它
so that you would not look for it in the most obvious place.
狼人就住在这里
The wolf lives here.
住在村里
In this village.
就在你们中间
Among you.
真正的凶手可能是你的邻居
The real killer could be your neighbor.
-什么  -你最好的朋友
- What? - Your best friend.
甚至你的妻子
Even your wife.
-封锁全村  -你不能这样
- Barricade the village. - You can't do that!
把守每个出口  杀死狼人前谁都不准离开
Post men at every gate! No one leaves until we kill the wolf!
-遵命  -狼人已经死了
- As you wish. - The wolf is dead.
今晚  我们庆祝狂欢
Tonight we celebrate!
好啊
Yes!
去吧  庆祝
Go ahead. Celebrate.
我们走着瞧
We'll see who is right.
狼人死啦
The wolf is dead!
面具摘了
Take it off!
我吸气  我吹气
I'll huff, and I'll puff...
我要吹倒你的房子
and I'll blow your house down!
那小个子真好笑
Laugh at the little man!
瓦莱丽  来跳舞啊
Valerie, come dance.
我吸气
I'll huff...
我吹气
I'll puff...
我要吹倒你的房子
and I'll blow your house down.
拍打拍打就干净了  我这样见教皇都行
I'll just flick this off. I'll be fit to see the pope.
爸爸
Papa.
你是我的好女儿
You're my good girl.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我知道  现在回家好吗
I know. Just go home now, okay?
逗你玩
Tricked you. Ha-ha-ha.
很不错
Impressive.
从哪儿学的
Where did you learn that?
克劳德
Claude.
克劳德  回去参加派对吧
Claude, come back to the party.
看来罗丝的裙下之臣又多了一个
Looks like Rose has a new conquest.
来  普鲁登斯
Come on, Prudence.
你丢下了我们
You left us!
冷静点  朋友
Take it easy, friend.
我说过我们不该分头行动  但你丢下了我们
I said we should stick together and you left us,
就是这样我父亲才死的
and my father is dead because of it!
别这样
Please don't do this.
别碰她  不然我砍掉你的手
Keep your hands off her or I'll cut them off!
彼得
Peter.
别跟着我
Leave me alone.
你干什么
What's the matter with you?
到底要我怎样  你才能不跟着我
What do I have to do to make you stop?
我爱你  彼得
I love you, Peter.
你跟罗丝怎么回事
What are you doing with Rose?
你根本不喜欢她
You don't even like her.
不用喜欢她  我就能从她身上得到我想要的
I don't have to like her to get what I want from her.
你不会撒谎
You're a terrible liar.
我知道你的感觉跟我一样
I know you feel like I do.
我知道你正欲火焚身
I know you're burning inside.
我永远也给不了你这种东西
I'll never be able to give you anything like this.
你以为我在意亨利的钱吗
Think I care about Henry's money?
你跟他才有未来
You have a future with him.
我不会让你自毁幸福
I'm not gonna let you ruin that.
我妈找你谈过是吗
Did my mother get to you?
瓦莱丽  我配不上你
Valerie, I'm wrong for you.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我会把你吃个一干二净
I could eat you up.
你不想要我吗
Don't you want me?
嘿   彼得
Hey, Peter.
来  帮个忙
Come on, give us a hand.
我只想跟你在一起
The only life I want is with you.
你刚刚去哪儿了
So where did you disappear to?
知道谷仓里那些干草有多柔软吗
You know all that soft hay in the granary?
-快跑  -去教堂
- Run! - Get to the church!
-彼得  -快走
-Peter! - Go!
克劳德
Claude!
你的死期到了  畜生
You will die now, beast!
狼人无法踏足圣地
The wolf can't cross onto holy ground!
去教堂
Get to the church!
The church!
克劳德
Claude!
现在  绑住它
Now! Rope it!
拖住它
Hold him!
克劳德
Claude!
-它太强了  -上帝更强
- It's strong. - God is stronger.
上帝更强
God is stronger!
我警告过你们
I warned you!
警告过你们
你们的狼人还活着
Your werewolf is still alive!
找到它
Find it!
Find it.
在那里
Over there!
你逃不出我的手掌心
You can't escape from me.
天哪  你会说话
Oh, my God. You can speak.
怎么可能
How?
是你听得懂我的话  就这么简单  瓦莱丽
You understand me. That's all that matters, Valerie.
你知道我的名字
You know my name.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
人的眼睛  深褐色
Human eyes, dark brown.
我很了解你
I know you well.
你想离开这个村子
You dream of leaving this village.
跟我走吧
Let me take you away.
你和我是一样的
You and I are the same.
不  我才不像你  杀人凶手
No, I'm nothing like you. You're a murderer.
你也是凶手  不是吗
You're a killer too, aren't you?
还记得那只兔子吗  瓦莱丽
What happened to the rabbit, Valerie?
我杀了它
I killed it.
我知道  所以跟我走吧
I know. So come with me.
不
No.
那街上将会血流成河  先从她开始
Then the streets will run red with blood. Starting with hers.
快点
Come on!
所罗门神父会阻止你的
Father Solomon will stop you.
所罗门神父也会像其他人一样必死无疑
Father Solomon will die like the rest.
血月结束前我还会回来找你
I'm coming back for you before the Blood Moon wanes.
那里  放箭
There! Fire!
你刚刚跟狼人说话了
You talked to the wolf.
不  是它跟我们说话
No, it talked to us.
不  那只是狼嚎
No, it growled.
等等  你听到它跟你说话了吗
Wait, you heard it talk to you?
他们会说我是巫婆  别告诉别人
They'll call me a witch. Don't tell anyone.
嗯  当然不会
No, of course not.
到圣地上来
Get inside onto holy ground.
等等  我要去找我弟弟
Wait, I have to find my brother.
-还有我的家人  -日出之前不准离开
- And my family. - No one leaves until sunrise.
-进去  -这是为了你们自己的安全
- Go. - For your own safety.
之前怀疑您是我们的不对  神父
We were wrong to have doubted you, Father.
我从没见过这么强的猛兽
I've never seen a beast as strong as this.
如此强大的生物
A creature this powerful
肯定血统纯正  由来已久了
must come from a long uninterrupted bloodline.
一代更比一代强
Each generation more potent than the one before.
我们必须找到它的人形
We must find it in its human form.
怎么找  谁都有可能
But how? It could be any of them.
要是一眼就能发现  它就活不了这么久
It hasn't survived this long by being obvious.
仔细找
Look everywhere.
各种标记
Look for the signs.
孤僻
Isolation.
巫术
Witchcraft.
黑魔法
The black arts.
异常行为
Abnormal behavior.
奇怪的气味
Strange smells.
每一家都要搜查
Your homes will be searched.
你们的秘密无处可藏
Your secrets brought to light.
你若无辜  则无需害怕
If you are innocent, you have nothing to fear.
但若有罪
But if you are guilty...
我向万能的上帝发誓
I swear by Almighty God...
我一定会消灭你
you will be destroyed.
他还活着
He's still alive!
给我水
Bring me water!
快点
Hurry!
现在是血月  所以他必须
It's a Blood Moon. So he must--
他是我弟弟
He's my brother!
被咬过的人就是受了诅咒
A man bitten... is a man cursed!
瓦莱丽  开开门
Valerie, open the door.
我们处境危险
We're all in danger.
得马上离开
So we've gotta leave now.
跟我走吧
Come away with me.
收拾好东西  我们必须马上走
Get your things. We have to leave now.
我不能跟你走  彼得
I can't go with you, Peter.
为什么
Why not?
对不起
I'm sorry.
发生什么了
What happened?
她会没事的
She's going to be all right.
狼人抓伤了她
The wolf just scratched her.
但不是咬伤
That's not a bite.
把她的头抬起来  瓦莱丽
Lift her head, Valerie.
来吧  喝了它  亲爱的
Here. Drink this, dear.
这有助于睡眠
It'll help you sleep.
睡吧
You sleep.
怎么了  亲爱的
What is it, darling?
怎么了
What is it?
狼人
The wolf.
它跟我说话了
It talked to me.
你能听懂它的话
And you understood it?
就像能听懂你的话一样
As clearly as I understand you.
这事你告诉过别人吗
Have you told anyone else about this?
只有罗克珊知道  但她不会告诉别人
Only Roxanne knows, but she won't tell anyone.
她甚至都不愿跟我说这事
She won't even talk to me about it.
它没有杀你
It chose not to kill you.
我想它希望我活着
I think it wants me alive.
-不  -再给我拿一条绷带
- No. - Bring me another bandage.
不
No.
我去打点清水
I have to get clean water.
克劳德回家了吗
Has Claude come home?
没人见过他
Nobody's seen him.
这边来  回屋里去  快点
There you go, back inside. Now.
你得让我们进去
You have to let us in.
我看见你跟彼得在一起
I saw you with Peter.
我知道你不希望我那样
I know you don't want me like that.
我不会逼你嫁给我
I'm not gonna force you to marry me.
我会中止婚约
I'm gonna break off the engagement.
对不起  亨利
I'm sorry, Henry.
够了
That's enough!
所罗门神父
Father Solomon!
我们发现有人藏在塔里
We found someone hiding in the tower!
快点
Quickly!
-是我弟弟  别碰他  -把他弄下来
- It's my brother! Don't touch him! - Get him down!
-审问他  -他不是狼人
-Interrogate him! - He's not the wolf!
看看他
Look at him!
他话都说不清  他在跟魔鬼交流
His speech is twisted. He communes with demons.
把他弄下来  马上
Get him down! Now!
他什么都没干
He hasn't done anything!
这是他研究巫术的证据
This is proof that he studies the black arts!
他是个巫师
He's a conjurer.
-我了解他  -比我了解我妻子还清楚吗
- I know him. - Better than I knew my own wife?
你永远不知道一个人有多少能耐
You never know what someone is capable of.
把他弄下来  快点
Get him down! Come on!
告诉我狼人的名字
Give me the name of the wolf.
告诉我名字
Give me the name.
快告诉我
Tell me the name!
这是罗马人发明的
The Romans invented this.
用来发掘真相的精妙方法
An ingenious system for extracting the truth.
他怎么能告诉你名字呢
How can he give you a name?
这孩子话都不会说
The boy can barely speak.
听听他如何歌颂对撒旦的爱吧
Listen to how he sings of his love of Satan.
我们这么做也是出于好意
We do this for the greater good.
这有什么好处
What's the good in this?
我杀了我妻子是为了保护我的孩子
I killed my wife to protect my children.
有时候  我们顺行天意的办法不尽人意
Our methods of pleasing God are sometimes flawed.
你最好能接受它
You had best develop a stomach for it.
她说有要事
She says it's important.
我是为释放我弟弟来跟你讲条件的
I've come to bargain for the release of my brother.
银指甲
Silver fingernails.
这样才能杀死狼人
To kill a werewolf.
出去
Get out.
求你了  除了钱我还有别的
Please, I have more than money to offer.
转过去
Turn around.
够了  走吧
Enough. Move.
等一下  求你了  我还有别的
Wait, please. I have something else.
放了我弟弟  我告诉你谁是巫女
Spare my brother and I'll give you the name of a witch.
现在
Now, that...
这还有点价值
is worth something.
把你跟我说的告诉他们
Tell them what you told me.
她能爬上最高的树
She can climb the tallest trees.
她比别的女孩儿跑得都快
She can run faster than all the girls.
她身穿红色的斗篷  那是魔鬼的颜色
She wears a red cloak. The devil's color.
胡说八道  那件斗篷是我做的
That's nonsense. I made that cloak.
安静  继续说
Silence! Continue.
她能跟狼人说话
And she can talk to werewolves.
我看到的  亲眼所见
I've seen it. With my own eyes.
你否认吗
Do you deny it?
不  我不否认
No, I don't deny it.
你们谈了些什么
And what was the nature of this conversation?
它说只要我跟它走  就不再骚扰剑角村
It promised to leave Daggerhorn in peace as long as I go with it.
狼人是村子里某个想要得到你的人  瓦莱丽
The wolf is someone in this village who wants you, Valerie.
你知道是谁吗
Do you know who it is?
要是换做我  我会努力想想
I'd think very hard if I were you.
告诉我
Tell me.
告诉我是谁
Tell me who it is.
告诉我名字
Give me a name.
它想要的是她  不是你们
It wants her, not you.
你们要想安保自身
If you wish to save yourselves,
只要就把它想要的给它就行
simply give it what it wants.
你不能把她交给那狼人
You can't give her to the wolf.
那是人类献祭
That's human sacrifice.
我们都牺牲了太多
We've all made sacrifices.
审判结束  都回家去吧
The trial is over. Go back to your homes.
我说了都回家去  所有人
I said go home. All of you!
我以为你在乎她呢
I thought you cared about her.
我是在乎她
I do care.
很在乎
我得想个好办法
I'm trying to be smart about it.
到谷仓去
Go to the granary.
你要去救她吗
You're gonna try and rescue her?
好吧  我要帮忙
Well, I'll help.
我还没绝望到要你帮忙
I'm not that desperate.
是吗  那你的计划是什么
Oh, really? Then what's your plan, huh?
看吧  你连计划都没有
See, you don't have one.
你已经见过那些锁了
Look, you've seen those locks.
我有一个铺子还有工具  你需要我
I've got a shop and I've got tools. You need me.
好吧
Okay. Fine.
不过  如果你就是狼人
But if you're the wolf,
我会把你的头砍下来
I'm gonna chop your head off.
我也一样
I will do the same to you.
很好
Fair enough.
回家去吧
Go home!
我弟弟在哪里
Where's my brother?
所罗门神父说你们会放了他
Father Solomon told me you'd release him.
我们已经放了
We did.
奶奶
Grandma.
这里有面包和毯子
Bread. Blanket.
你还要别的吗
Do you need anything else?
我希望你别用到那把刀
I do not want you to use that knife.
-我们必须找到狼人  -在日落之前吗
- We have to find the wolf. - By sundown?
听着  狼人想要的是你
Listen, the wolf wants you.
但是它先杀了你姐姐
But first it killed your sister.
不  我不知道
No. I didn't know it,
但是露西爱上了亨利
but Lucie was in love with Henry.
当她发现我订了婚
And when she found out about my engagement...
就她把自己交给了狼人
...she gave herself to the wolf.
不  露西不会那么做
No. Lucie wouldn't do that.
-时间到了  -但她可能是对亨利有所回应
- Your time is up. - But she might have responded to Henry.
请把这些交给她
Please see that she gets that.
蠢货
Oaf.
塞泽尔
Cesaire.
我会救回你的女儿  然后跟她结婚
I'm gonna save your daughter. And then I intend to marry her.
我希望得到你的祝福
I'd like your blessing in this,
要是没有祝福也没关系
but I can live without it.
我能做点什么
What can I do?
我们关门了
We're closed.
是我
It's me.
你好  亨利
Hello, Henry.
-我给你带了些饼干  -谢谢
- I brought you some biscuits. - Thanks.
我想谢谢你早上说的那些
I just wanna thank you for speaking up this morning.
来试试吧
Here, try some.
很好
Yes.
你很勇敢
That was very brave of you.
我只是实话实说
I said what I felt.
你知道
You know...
我希望你明白
...I want you to know you're
你并没有义务维护瓦莱丽
under no obligation to stand up for Valerie.
你不再是她的未婚夫
You're no longer engaged to her.
她爱上了别人
She's in love with someone else.
并不意味着我就不能再关心她
That doesn't mean I've stopped caring about her.
我想露西也是这样对你的
I imagine that's just how Lucie felt about you.
她有一点喜欢我
She had a crush on me.
不仅仅是喜欢
Oh, more than a crush.
我觉得她会为了你做任何事
I think she would have done absolutely anything for you.
即使要她在狼人出没的夜晚跟你见面
Even agree to meet you on a wolf night
只要你说她就会去
if you asked her to.
你这是什么意思
Why are you doing this?
你认为我是狼人吗
Do you think I'm the wolf?
你是在指责我是凶手吗
Are you accusing me of murder?
我没指责你什么
I'm not accusing you of anything.
我只是想找出真相
I just want to find out the truth.
是你
It's you.
天哪  是你  我能在你身上闻到那味道
My god, it's you. I can smell it on you.
你在我身上闻到什么味道了
Heh. What can you smell on me?
我父亲死的那晚
The night my father died,
我闻到了狼人的味道
I could smell the wolf.
像是一种很浓的麝香味
It was like a deep musk.
我现在你身上也闻到了这种味道
And I can smell it all over you right now.
你大晚上的  独自一人
What do you do out there in that cabin
在那小屋里做什么
all by yourself in the middle of the night?
露西死的那晚
On the night that Lucie died?
你不知道  对吧
You don't know, do you?
我知道你在做什么
I know what you're doing.
我不会让你把事情推到我身上
And I'm not gonna let you turn this on me.
你跟我们走
You're coming with us.
我什么都没做
I haven't done anything.
以防万一
Just a precaution.
所罗门神父不想巫女的家人惹什么麻烦
Father Solomon doesn't want any trouble from the witch's family.
是时候穿上你妖女的袍子了
It's time to put on your harlot's robe.
瓦莱丽
Valerie.
我尽了最大的努力保护你们
I did my best to protect you.
你和露西
You and Lucie.
我知道  爸爸
I know, Papa.
你教我们要坚强
You taught us to be strong.
所罗门神父设计了这个面具  好让大家羞辱我
Father Solomon had designed the mask for public disgrace.
即使是我的朋友也盯着我批判我
And even my friends stared, judging me.
停下
Stop.
如果他们是对的呢
What if they were right?
也许狼人知道些我所不知的
Maybe the wolf knew something I didn't.
也许我的内心的确藏有黑暗的东西
Maybe there was something dark inside of me.
大家都回家去吧
You should all go home!
对不起  瓦莱丽
I'm so sorry, Valerie.
我没想到事情会这样
I didn't mean for this to happen.
祝福你  亲爱的
Bless you, my dear.
普鲁登斯
Prudence.
瓦莱丽
Valerie?
罗克珊让我转告说她很抱歉
Roxanne wanted me to tell you how sorry she is.
她那么说是为了救她弟弟
She said those things to save her brother.
我明白  告诉她我不怪她
I know. Tell her that I forgive her.
我会的
Of course.
但是我想说
But I wanted to say....
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
你什么都不用说了
But you don't have to say anything.
但是我想说
But I want to.
我希望你知道
I want you to know that...
你也许骗得了罗克珊
...you may have fooled Roxanne...
但是你骗不了我
...but you don't fool me.
再也不会了
Not anymore.
你总是那么好
You were always too good.
那么漂亮
Too pretty.
那么完美
Too perfect.
你欺骗了我们
You tricked us.
现在你要得到应有的惩罚
Now you're gonna get what you deserve.
普鲁登斯  我想你该走了
Prudence, I think you should go.
是的
Yes.
不会太久的
It won't be long now.
狼人马上就来了
The wolf is coming.
狼人就住在这里
The wolf lives here.
你的邻居  你最好的朋友
Your neighbor. Your best friend.
甚至可能是你的妻子
Even your wife.
你很漂亮
You're the pretty one.
-我会把你吃个一干二净  -你会快乐起来的
- I could eat you up. - You will be happy again.
人的眼睛  深褐色
Human eyes, dark brown.
我很了解你
I know you well.
知道怎么杀老虎吗  奥古斯特神父
Do you know how you kill a tiger, Father Auguste?
拴上最好的山羊做诱饵
You tie out your best goat...
然后等待
and wait.
着火了
Fire!
快救火
Put it out!
快去
Go!
我带你离开这里
I'm gonna get you out of here.
火势太大
It's too much!
别动
Don't move.
在那  他上钩了  放箭
There! He's taken the bait! Fire!
等等  那不是狼人
Wait, that's not the wolf!
他在帮巫女
He's aiding a witch!
-放箭  -不要
- Fire! - No!
快跑
Run!
跑
Run.
就是他放的火
This one started the fire.
把他关起来  关到铜象里去
Lock him up. In the elephant!
-走  -带走
- Go! - Move it!
巫女已经跑了
The witch has escaped!
过来集合  找出巫女
Get over here! Find the witch!
快点  彼得带了马和我们汇合
Come on, Peter's meeting us with the horses.
瓦莱丽
Valerie!
彼得在哪
Where's Peter?
我不知道
I don't know.
他说他会来
He said he'd be here.
如果他没出现
If he doesn't show...
就由我带你走
I'm gonna take you away.
让我带你走吧
Let me take you away.
你认为我是狼人吗
Do you think I'm the wolf?
找出巫女
Find the witch!
快点  快
Come on! Quickly!
走
Go.
那边
That way!
我们应该去教堂
We should go to the church.
狼人不能踏入圣地
The wolf can't cross onto holy ground.
部分人跟我走  这边  我们走
Some with me! This way! Let's go!
我听到那边有声音
I heard something over there.
他们在这  快追
They're in here! After them!
瓦莱丽
Valerie.
亨利  亨利
Henry. Henry.
快走  瓦莱丽  走
Go. Valerie, go!
不  我不会丢下你的
No. I'm not leaving you.
我们请求庇护
We claim sanctuary.
你还没进入圣地呢
You are not on holy ground yet.
这...
This...
是我的
belongs to me.
你想要她活命
You want her alive?!
杀了它
Kill it!
瓦莱丽
Valerie.
跨出这道门  不然我就灭了这个村子
Step across the gate, or I'll destroy this village.
趁太阳还没升起  跟我走
Come with me before the sun rises.
做决定吧
Make your decision.
我不会让你毁了我的家园
I won't let you destroy my home.
-我跟你走  -不要  瓦莱丽  不
- I'll go with you. - Don't! Valerie. No.
如果你保证不伤害他们
If you promise to leave them alone.
不  我不会让你为了我们而牺牲自己
No. I won't let you sacrifice yourself for us.
-我也不会  -我也不会
- Nor will I.  - Nor will l.
我支持瓦莱丽
I stand by Valerie.
你躲不过我的
You can't hide from me.
这巫女还是要被烧死
The witch will still burn!
血月之下
Under the Blood Moon...
被咬过的人就是受了诅咒
A man bitten is a man cursed.
我的孩子将成为孤儿
My children will be orphaned.
我的弟弟
My brother...
也有孩子
had children too.
我并无恶意
I meant only to serve.
我只想保护我们远离黑暗
To protect us from darkness.
血月之下
Under the Blood Moon...
被咬过的人就是受了诅咒
A man bitten is a man cursed.
彼得在哪
Where's Peter?
奶奶
Grandmother.
你的眼睛好大
What big eyes you have.
为了把你看得更清楚啊  宝贝
The better to see you with, my dear.
奶奶  你的耳朵好大
Grandmother, what big ears you have.
为了听清楚你说的话啊  宝贝
The better to hear you with, my dear.
你的牙齿也好大
What big teeth you have.
这样更方便吃掉你啊  宝贝
The better to eat you with, my dear.
瓦莱丽  你怎么起床了
Valerie. What are you doing out of bed?
我很担心
I was so worried.
看起来好多了
It looks much better.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
奶奶家  我想她有危险
To Grandmother's. I think she's in danger.
趁狼人的足迹还没被风雪掩盖
We're going after the wolf
我们现在就去找它
before the storm can cover its tracks.
它还会变回人形  然后我们就能杀掉它
It'll be human again and we can finally kill it.
还有我...
And I have....
什么  告诉我
What? Tell me.
彼得还是下落不明
Peter is still missing.
我会尽我所能
I'll do what I have to do.
千万要小心
Please be careful.
瓦莱丽
Valerie.
谢天谢地你一切都好
Thank God you're all right.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我整晚都被关在那铜象里
I was trapped in that brazen beast all night.
终于逃了出来
I finally broke out.
别靠近我
Don't come near me.
怎么了  瓦莱丽
Valerie, what?
你不相信我吗
You don't believe me?
我会伤害你
I'll hurt you.
不  你不会的
No, you won't.
别过来
Please don't.
奶奶
Grandmother!
奶奶  你还好吗
Grandmother, are you all right?
我做了个噩梦
I had a nightmare.
我很好
I'm fine.
我刚醒来
I just woke up.
你要是饿了  可以喝点汤
There's some soup if you're hungry.
我觉得狼人在这附近
I think the wolf is out there.
没关系  亲爱的  这里很安全
It's all right, darling. We're safe in here.
吃吧  记住
Eat up. Remember
-面包可以缓解忧伤  -缓解忧伤
- "All sorrows are less with bread."  - "Less with bread".
这就对了
That's right.
把它吃光  亲爱的
Eat up, my dear.
这是什么
What is this?
爸爸  你在这儿干嘛
Father, what are you doing here?
奶奶呢
Where's Grandmother?
我别无选择
I had no choice.
她终于意识到了我是谁
She finally realized what I am.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do this?
坐下
Sit down.
瓦莱丽
Oh, Valerie.
我一直不受尊重
I've been so disrespected.
我的付出得不到应有的回报
I've settled for far less than I deserve.
于是
So
我决定离开
I decided I'd leave.
去城里
For the city.
那里是更好的猎场
For richer hunting grounds.
为什么不直接离开
Why didn't you just leave?
因为我爱你们  我的女儿们
Because I loved you girls.
我希望你们和我一起走
I wanted you to come with me.
-但你必须等到血月的时候  -没错
- But you had to wait for the Blood Moon. - Yes.
根据常理
By birthright...
礼物应先由我的大女儿获得
the gift would go first to my eldest daughter.
所以我伪造了一封信
So I forged a letter.
但当我试图跟她对话的时候
But when I tried to speak to her--
亨利不会来了  露西
Henry's not coming, Lucie.
她听不懂我说的话
--she didn't understand me.
我的孩子  流着我狼人血液的孩子
Any offspring of mine with my wolf blood
都应该能听懂
would've been able to do so.
一切都真相大白了
And then it all made sense.
露西不可能是我的女儿
Lucie couldn't be my daughter.
你妈妈骗了我
Your mother lied to me.
你早就知道  对吧
But you knew that already, didn't you?
这些年来我一直小心谨慎
After all these years of being so clever and so careful,
结果还是失控了
I just lost control.
我对不起露西
I'm sorry for Lucie.
你报复了妈妈
You took revenge on mother.
还有她的情人
And her lover.
那晚  亨利闻出了狼人的气味
Henry smelled the wolf that night.
昨天也是
And then again yesterday.
他以为这气味来自你奶奶
He thought the smell came from your grandmother.
但她伴着这气味过了一辈子
But she had lived with that smell her whole life.
要知道  我的父亲也是狼人
You see, my father was a wolf too.
他衣服上还留着那股味道
The smell remained on his clothing.
直到母亲临死前
Mother never knew what it meant...
她才知道这意味着什么
till the moment she died.
我很爱她
I loved her.
她和露西  我从没想过要伤害她们
Her and Lucie both. I never wanted to hurt them.
瓦莱丽  跟我一起走吧
Valerie, come with me.
这是血月的最后一天
It's the last day of the Blood Moon.
只要咬一下  你就会和我一样
One bite, and you'll be like me.
我不会和你一样
I won't do what you do.
我不能
I can't.
你可以的  瓦莱丽
Yes, you can, Valerie.
你的血管里流淌着我的血
My blood already courses through your veins.
这是礼物
It's a gift.
是我父亲给我的礼物
It's a gift my father gave to me
现在我也可以给你
that now I can give to you.
我比他强
I'm stronger than he was,
你甚至可以比我更强
you'll be even stronger than me.
想想看吧
Think about it.
我们将会所向披靡
We will be invincible.
上帝一定存在  因为你就是那恶魔
There must be a God, because you're the devil.
而你是恶魔的女儿
And you're the devil's daughter.
日出时  你就没那么可怕了
You're not so terrifying when the sun is up.
你怎么知道
How would you know?
爸爸
Papa!
我有东西要给你
I have something for you.
彼得
Peter.
带我离开这里
Get me out of here.
他咬了我
He bit me.
月亮升起时
When the moon rises...
我也会像他一样
I'll be like him.
变成一头野兽
A beast.
我所知的一切都被颠覆了
Everything I knew was ripped apart.
我所见的一切都变了
I saw it all differently.
全是谎言  母亲的  父亲的
All the lies. My mother's, my father's.
他是我仅剩的全部
He was all I had left.
彼得
Peter.
即使我怀疑他
Even when I doubted him...
即时我伤害他
even when I wounded him...
彼得一直是真诚的
Peter was true.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你父亲的事不能让人知道
No one can know about your father.
不然他们会绞死你
They'll hang you...
只因你是狼人的女儿
for being the daughter of the wolf.
彼得
Peter.
我必须得离开
I have to leave.
你和我在一起不安全
You won't be safe with me...
在我学会怎样保护你之前
until I learn how to protect you from....
我会等你
I'll wait for you.
我就知道你会这么说
I thought you'd say that.
这是我记忆中最残酷的冬天
It was the most brutal winter I could remember.
剑角村又回到了往日的平静
Daggerhorn fell back into its old rhythms.
狼人没有再出现
The wolf didn't come back.
但村民仍然生活在恐惧之中
But the village still lived in fear.
这是他们唯一所知的生活
It was the only life they knew.
亨利找到了勇气
Henry found his courage.
他选择了光荣的人生之路
He chose a life of honor
保护我们远离黑暗
protecting us from darkness.
随着时间推移  母亲明白
With time, my mother realized that
父亲再也不会回到剑角村
father would never return Daggerhorn.
我不能再待在那里
But I could no longer live there.
那有我的秘密
with my secret